立法會主席。
請議員就座。
The MSW Management Strategy.
發言，石禮謙議員就政府帳目委員會第六十五號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議員。
作為回覆是滿意的，無公開聽證會，進行這些六章節。
Could better understand whether the training programmes conducted by the centre for persons with disabilities, are value for money.
Thank you, Mr. President. On behalf of the Public Accounts Committee, I have the honour to table our report number 65 today.
effective manner. This is reflected in their failure in meeting all the main waste management targets set in 2005.
我會簡要報告給理事會關於委員會結論和建議的四章節，其中包含更嚴重的不規則或不足。
The committee urges the administration to consider developing a new and realistic blueprint in view of the inadequacy set up in the report of the committee and the director of audit.
Out of the ten chapters covered by the directors' of audit report number sixty-five, the committee has decided to hold hearings on four chapters that contain more serious allegations of irregularities or shortcomings.
The committee has also studied the other six chapters by asking the relevant bureaux, departments and public organisations to provide written replies on their measures to address the inadequacies raised in the director of audits' report.
Regarding the issues relating to Shine Scale Centre raised in Chapter 10 of the Director of Audits report, the committee has also conducted a visit to the centre at Pakfulam run by the Vocational Training Council. Through the visit, the committee members.
The first two subjects studied by the committee are related. They are the administration's effort in managing municipal solid waste, hereafter known as MSW, and the reduction and the recycling of food waste, which is a type of MSW. For the manage
of M.S.W.， the committee expresses alarm and finds it unacceptable that the that the environment bureau and the environment protection department lack the determination to execute the action plans to manage M.S.W. in a professional and
and in providing accurate and complete information, such as the remaining serviceable lives of the landfills and the estimations of the MSW generation quantities and its recovery rates, to the Legislative Council to facilitate the discussion on.
係。
disposed.
Treatment facilities will be essential for their successful operation.
委員會表達關切，這組合的《香港報》將 undermine 過其運作的效率。
第三個主題，先生，我會簡報，是委員會的關心，關於使用和 disposal of vacant school premises。
委員會 urge the secretary for commerce and economic development and postmaster general to review the operation mode of the Hong Kong post and explore measures to provide enhance.
作為一間貿易基金，自1995年以來，它 enjoys flexibility in deploying the revenue on a self-financing basis. But as a government department, it also needs to follow government rules and regulations.
就係關於分配和使用上述場地。最後一個主題是關於香港郵政的運作問題。香港郵政有責任提供一般郵政服務給公眾，以可負擔的價格。
flexibility to facilitate the Hong Kong post operation. Lastly, I wish to record my appreciation of the contribution made by members of the committee. Our gratitude goes to witnesses who attended the hearings held by the committee.
for the footways issue, the committee expresses great dissatisfaction and disappointment that the environmental bureau and the EPD have only taken piecemeal actions to address the problem. EPD has not taken timely and proactive actions to monitor the.
Effectiveness of the food waste campaign. There is also a lack of coordination from EPD to solicit support from other government departments to lead by example in reducing food waste. The committee expresses great dissatisfaction and again finds it unnecessary.
不可接受，That EPD has not implemented the organic waste treatment facility phase one project in a responsible and professional manner. EPD significantly underestimated project costs when it consulted the relevant panel of the legislative con.
2010， due to retendering of the project arising from the higher than expected tender prices received， the commissioning of the phase one project have been delayed from 2013 to 2017. During this period， the footways have been and would be
off at the landfills. The committee urges the administration to foster a cultural shift and engage the whole community's effort in reducing food waste. An effective system for separating, collecting and transporting sufficient food waste to the organic waste.
The committee expresses great great dismay and finds it unacceptable that the education bureau and the lands department had not managed the allocate allocate and allocate the vacant school premises under their respective purviews effectively for meeting different needs of the society.
The database maintained by the Education Bureau on the Wakan School premises is not comprehensive and useful to facilitate the effective management of the premises. The Committee urges the Education Bureau to update the Wakan School premises database and formulate a policy.
無立法效力嘅議案辯論。
致謝議案，咁梁君彥議員係會動議。
I would also like to express our gratitude to the director of audit and his colleagues for their unfailing support. Last but not least, I like to thank the secretary for their hard work. Thank you, Mr. President.